CURRICULUM VITAE

SATHE PRASHANT D.



Contact Information:

FL No.C-9, Shree Hans Nagar, S 67/1B/19, Gokul Nagar, Dhanori, Pune-411015 Mobile No: 08600538691

Residence Phone: 020-20260011 Email: sathepdiit@gmail.com

Key Qualifications:

Experience in Seismic Analysis, Dynamic Analysis of the structure and Earthquake Resistant Structural Design, Hydraulic structures, Response of Buildings, Dams, Power House structures, Preparation of Drawings in Hydro Power Projects.

Well versed with Indian Standard Codes and various Earthquake Resistant Analysis and Design Software's like ANSYS, Auto CAD, ETABS V9&SAFE, SAP, STAAD PRO and MS Office etc.

Education:



M.Tech. in Structural Dynamics (2008-2010) from Earthquake Engineering Department, Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee, India.

[Established in 1847, the second oldest engineering college in Asiawww.iitr.ac.in]



B.Tech. in Civil Engineering (2004-2008) from Government College of Engineering, Pune, India.

[Established in 1854, the third oldest engineering college in Asia-www.coep.org.in]

Employment Record:

- 1. January, 2012 to current date: Assistant Professor, MAEER'S MIT, Pune.
- 2. September, 2011 to December, 2011: Structural Engineer, Dar Al-Handasha, Shair and Partners, Pune.
 - Detail Design of Residential and Commercial Buildings as per ACI, ASCE codes.
- 3. August, 2010 to August, 2011: Structural Engineer, Consulting Engineering Services (India) Private Limited, New Delhi
 - Detail Design and Engineering
 - Jindal Pump House for (4x600 MW), Thermal Power Plant, Raigarh, Chhattisgarh.

- Detail Design and Engineering
 - New Umtru H.E. Project (2x20 MW), Meghalaya.
- Preparation & Compilation of Technical Proposal
 - Involved in preparation and compilation of Technical
 - Proposal of Hydro Power Project.

Training Course/ Work Shops/ Seminars attended:

- 1. Participation in the workshop titled "**Concrete Mix Design**" held in Dept. Of Applied Mechanics in Government College of Engineering Pune (March 2006).
- Participation in the workshop titled "<u>Earthquake Resistant Design of RCC</u>
 <u>Buildings</u>" held in Dept. Of Applied Mechanics in Government College of Engineering Pune (December 2007).
- 3. Participation in the national research conference on <u>Disaster Mitigation In</u>

 <u>Housing In India: An Agenda A For Future (HDMFA 2010)</u> held by

 Center Of Excellence In Disaster Mitigation And Management, IIT, Roorkee.

Research Paper Published:

1. My Research Paper Named "<u>Estimation Of Governing Parameters of The Structure Subjected to Ground Motion Using Transfer Function Approach</u>" was accepted for the 14th Symposium on Earthquake Engineering (14SEE) Scheduled on December 17-19, 2010 at IIT, Roorkee.

Project Work:

1. Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Estimation of Governing Stress in Structures Subjected to Ground Motion Using Transfer Function Approach (2010).

- Estimation of Transfer Function for G+8 RCC Building.
- 2. Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Parametric Study of Cracking in a Concrete Gravity Dam (2009).

- Determination of Location of Crack in a Concrete Gravity Dam Subjected to Ground Motion.
- 3. **Government College of Engineering, Pune**

Fiber Reinforced Polymer (2008).

- Study of Fiber Reinforced Polymer Properties and Design of Foot over Bridge using FRP.
- 4. Government College of Engineering, Pune

Design of G+3 R.C.C. Building (2007).

Earthquake Resistant Design of R.C.C. Building.

Membership in Professional Societies:

Life member (LM 1431) of **Indian Society of Earthquake Technology** (2009).

Computer Proficiency:

Knowledge of ANSYS, Auto CAD, ETABS V9&SAFE, SAP, STAAD PRO, MS Office and Management Software MS Project etc.

Languages:

Languages	Speak	Read	Write
Hindi	Yes	Yes	Yes
English	Yes	Yes	Yes
Marathi	Yes	Yes	Yes

Personal Information:

Name : SATHE PRASHANT DASHARATH

Father's Name : Shri. SATHE DASHARATH BAPU

Gender : Male

Date of Birth : 6th September 1986

Marital Status : Unmarried

Permanent Address : Fl No.C-9,

Shree Hansnagar, S.No. 67/1B/19,

Gokulnagar, Dhanori,

Pune (Maharashtra)-411015.

Nationality : Indian

Passport Status : Valid Upto 06-05-2018

References:

Name	Designation	Contact	Location
Dr. Ashok D Pandey	Associate Professor	+91-01332-285531 (<u>adpanfeq@iitr.ernet.in</u>)	IIT, Roorkee
Dr. Ashok Kumar	Professor	+91-01332-285527 (akmegfeg@iitr.ernet.in)	IIT, Roorkee

Educational Qualifications Year and CGPA*/%

EXAM	YEAR	% MARKS/SGPA		CLASS/CGPA	
		I st SEM	II nd SEM		
M.TECH. (II nd Yr)	2009-10	8.00	8.00	7.96	
M.TECH. (I st Yr)	2008-09	7.67	8.17	(I st -Distinction)	
GATE	2008			82.32%	
в.тесн.	2007-08	8.00	7.04	6.77	
T.Y.B.TECH	2006-07	7.56	6.40		
S.Y.B.TECH	2005-06	6.58	6.33	(I st)	
F.Y.B.TECH	2004-05	5.96	6.13		
HSC	2003-04	79.50% (PHY-94/100,MATHS- 95/100,CHEM-78/100)		I st -Distinction	
SSC	2001-02	74%		I st	

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the particulars furnished above are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Pune

Date: (SATHE PRASHANT D.)